carbyn.com 2014-06-28

# Privacy Policy « Synacor

## [](http://www.synacor.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/trusteseal.png)

Synacor, Inc. (“Synacor”) ensures that the personal information of its clients’ end users will be kept safe and confidential. The following is **Synacor’s Privacy Policy** :

#### Introduction

Synacor is a global technology company providing Internet solutions to enable its clients, media companies and advertisers to build close relationships with consumers on the Internet. We provide and manage web portals, email and other services (“Services”) to and for our clients (which include ISPs, computer electronics manufacturers, charities, and other companies) on their websites (“Client Websites”). Synacor also provides advertising on its Client Websites and to third parties for their websites (“Advertising Services”).

Synacor considers the privacy and security of the information of its users and its client’s end users to be very important. The following privacy policy explains how Synacor collects and uses information a) obtained in connection with its Client Websites, and b) obtained when you visit the [www.synacor.com](http://www.synacor.com/) and [www.synacor.net](http://www.synacor.net/) websites (“Synacor Websites”).

Synacor has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your information. The TRUSTe program only covers information that may be collected through the Client Websites, or through [www.synacor.com](http://www.synacor.com/) or [www.synacor.net](http://www.synacor.net/). TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacypolicy@synacor.com](mailto:privacypolicy@synacor.com).If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

Synacor complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personally identifiable information (“PII”) from the European Union member countries. Synacor has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Synacor’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

### Information Collection and Use on the Client Websites

#### Information Collected and How We Use It

We collect information (which may include login, password, or other personal information) via the Client Websites when you choose to provide it to us and/or from our Clients. In addition, you or our Client may provide demographic information (such as zip code, or age), or other information as part of registration, sign-in, completing surveys, or otherwise. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of the special features of the Client Websites. Please note that we do not control the data, we only act as a data processor of this data on behalf of our Clients. As a data processor, we will not share, sell, rent, or trade with third parties for their marketing purposes any PII collected by us, unless you direct us to do so.

Synacor may work with third party service providers to augment some of the information you provide on the Client Websites. For example, if you have provided your email address via the Client Websites, we may work with a third party data company to determine your age and zip code, and add that information to our database.

Synacor uses the information provided to us in order to improve the quality of the Client Websites, provide you with customized content according to your preferences, and provide anonymous aggregate reporting for internal and external clients, including disclosing some aggregate information and user statistics to current and prospective clients, advertisers, and content partners in order to describe our services.

Synacor may also use e-mail addresses and other information to respond to users who communicate with us for support purposes or otherwise. If you choose to correspond with Synacor through e-mail, Synacor may retain the content of the correspondences, the e-mail addresses and its responses.

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information Collected Automatically

We collect non-personally identifiable traffic data (“Non-PII”) from our Client Websites. Non-PII includes, but is not limited to, information such as your IP address, web pages on the Client Websites which have been viewed by you, date and time, domain type, and the URL of the website from which you entered the Client Website. This type of information may be collected using different types of technologies, such as cookies and web beacons. Synacor uses Non-PII to help diagnose problems with its server, analyze trends and administer the Client Websites.

Your IP address is not linked by Synacor to PII, but it is used to gather broad demographic data and to monitor statistics to improve our Services. IP addresses are also used to provide an audit trail in the case of any attempted illegal or unauthorized use of the Synacor Websites or Client Websites.

#### Cookies and Web Beacons

“Cookies” are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer’s hard disk to enable saving of your website preferences and for other record-keeping purposes. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user’s computer. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to enjoy certain features of the Synacor Websites or Client Websites.

A “web beacon” consists of a small string of software code that represents an often-transparent graphic image, usually no larger than 1 pixel x 1 pixel, that is placed on a website or in an e-mail.

Synacor uses cookies to deliver content specific to end user interests and, with user permission, to save passwords to prevent the need for you to re-enter your password each time you visit that Client Website. Synacor uses cookies or web beacons to collect anonymous data such as site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, advertising auditing and reporting, and personalization. Cookies and web beacons help Synacor understand, report, and enhance your experience while on the Client Websites.

**Flash LSOs**

We use local storage objects (LSOs) to store content information and preferences. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use LSOs to collect and store information.

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>

### Advertising on the Client Websites

#### Information Collected on the Client Websites Related to Advertising Services

Synacor provides, manages, and tracks online advertising campaigns on our Client Websites and on third party websites. As part of this Advertising Service, Synacor may, through the use of cookies and web beacons, collect aggregate data from users of such websites, including but not limited to, your IP address, the type of browser used, which of such websites have been visited, which of the ads we provided have been viewed or clicked on, and the date and time the online ads were viewed and/or clicked. Synacor does not collect or use PII related to the Advertising Service, and we do not merge and PII with any of the Non-PII collected related to the Advertising Service.

Cookies and web beacons, as used with the Advertising Services, help Synacor understand, report, and enhance the relevance of its online advertising campaigns. As indicated above, you can set your browser to stop accepting cookies, but in doing so you may not be able to enjoy the full functionality of many of the websites you visit.

#### Third Parties and the Advertising Service

Synacor works with advertising companies who deliver ads for us on the Client Websites or through content that is accessible via the Client Websites. Such advertising companies may use cookies and/or web beacons to uniquely distinguish your web browser and keep track of information relating to serving ads on your web browser, such as the type of ads shown and the web pages on which the ads appeared. Synacor may, and may allow third parties to, employ cookies or web beacons in order to compile aggregated statistics regarding the effectiveness of the promotional campaigns or other operations of the Client Websites. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. We do not grant any third parties the right to collect or access your PII using cookies or web beacons, but these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies. Synacor encourages you to be aware of the privacy policies of these companies before you choose to allow them to place a cookie or web beacon for your web browser. You should also consult these companies’ privacy policies if you wish to opt-out of receiving cookies or web beacons from these companies. Synacor has no access to or control over these third parties’ cookies or web beacons.

#### Opt-ing Out

You may opt out of receiving targeted advertising from a number of advertising companies which may be providing ads for the Client Websites by visiting [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or [http://preferences.truste.com](http://preferences.truste.com/).

Please note that opting out of receiving targeted advertising will not eliminate the display of advertising on the Client Websites. Rather, it only eliminates the use of Non-PII in determining which ads are displayed.

### Controlling the use of your information

#### Sharing of Information by Synacor.

Synacor will not share, sell, rent or trade PII collected on the Client Websites or from our Clients with third parties for promotional purposes. We will not share your PII with any individuals or non-affiliate companies except in the following circumstances:

Protection of Synacor and others: We reserve the right to disclose information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served upon us.

Business Transfers: Synacor may transfer any information in our possession to any successor to all or substantially all of its business or assets that concern the Services.

Aggregation: Synacor may share aggregated usage and demographic information collected via the Client Websites and Services. However, no PII will be included in these aggregations.

Affiliated Business We Do Not Control: We are affiliated with a variety of businesses that jointly provide products or services with Synacor. When an affiliated business is associated with your transaction, we will share information that is related to such transactions with that affiliated business.

#### Sharing Your Own Information with Others.

If you choose to post comments to blogs, forums, or other editorial sections of the Client Websites, any information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of such website. Therefore, when using blogs, forums, other editorial sections of the Client Websites, or otherwise posting information online, we urge you to think carefully about including any information (name, address, passwords, medical information, or otherwise) that might be used to identify you or your family members. We are not responsible for the information you choose to submit through these features.

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users.

#### Information Relating to Children

Neither Synacor’s Websites, the Client Websites, nor the Services are designed for those 13 years of age and younger. Synacor does not knowingly collect PII from anyone under the age of 13. If the company is made aware that it has received PII from someone under 13, it will use reasonable efforts to remove that information from its records. Children under the age of 13 should not post in any of the blogs, forums, or other editorial sections of the Synacor Websites or the Client Websites.

#### Updating/Accessing/Amending/Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If you are a user of our Client Websites, the information provided through those websites is owned and controlled by Synacor’s Clients. Please check the privacy policy on the Client Website for instructions on how to modify your personal information with the owner of that information.

If you are a user of Synacor’s Website and would like us to update, correct, delete, or deactivate any personal information that you have provided to us on such website, please send your request to us at [privacypolicy@synacor.com](mailto:privacypolicy@synacor.com) and we will process your request within a reasonable period of time after receipt, not to exceed thirty (30) days.

#### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacypolicy@synacor.com](mailto:privacypolicy@synacor.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Social Media (Features) and Widgets

The Synacor Websites and Client Websites may include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on the Client Websites or the Synacor Websites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on the sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Client Websites or Synacor Websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

#### Security Procedures

Synacor has implemented a variety of security measures to protect PII received by Synacor, including containing all PII behind its secured server network and limiting its accessibility to a limited number of authorized persons who have special access rights to such systems. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the PII submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your PII, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### Additional Information

Synacor’s Website and the Client Websites may contain links to other sites. Synacor is not responsible for the privacy practices, the content or the products and services offered by such websites. Because we cannot control the activities of third parties, we cannot accept responsibility for any use of your PII by such third parties, and we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the same privacy practices as Synacor. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of any other service provider from whom you request services. If you visit a third party website that is linked to the Synacor Websites or the Client Websites, you should read that site’s privacy statement before providing any PII.

### Changes to this Policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here prior to the change becoming effective.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on **May 19, 2014**.

Questions about this privacy statement, the practices or dealing with Synacor’s Websites should be directed to:

Synacor, Inc.  
Privacy Policy Administrator  
40 La Riviere Drive, Suite 300  
Buffalo, NY 14202  

In addition to the policies above, the following items refer specifically to [www.synacor.com](http://www.synacor.com/).

We do not collect any PII on this website unless you apply for a job. If you apply for a job, we will collect through our job application service provider, such information including your name, email, address, phone number and resume. We utilize framing techniques to make it appear that the user is still on the website when the user is actually on a third party website.

We use a third party service provider to manage our job postings and resume submission. This third party is prohibited from using your PII for promotional purposes.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about a job on the website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. We do not store this information.

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our website which may contain PII. We do obtain the customer’s consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial, comments or reviews removed please contact us at [privacypolicy@synacor.com](mailto:privacypolicy@synacor.com).

You will not receive any communications from the website unless you contact us for a specific request or submit a job application. See above how to modify your PII submitted.
